<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anand Kumar</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/Website/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Anand Kumar</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 22:25:12 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/Website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>URL_Shortener</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Website/projects/url_shortener/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 22:25:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Website/projects/url_shortener/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FileCompression</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Website/projects/filecompression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 22:16:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Website/projects/filecompression/</guid>
      <description>File compression is a technique used to reduce the size of a file by encoding its data in a more efficient way. This is done to save storage space and improve transmission speed. There are various compression algorithms available, such as ZIP, GZIP, and BZIP2, which can be used to compress different types of files. Compressed files need to be decompressed before they can be used again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structs_VS_Classes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Website/post/structs_vs_classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 21:57:34 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Website/post/structs_vs_classes/</guid>
      <description>What are Structs? Structs are similar to classes in that they represent data structures that can contain data members and function members. Structs are best used when you need to represent simple data types, such as integers, strings, or other basic data types.&#xA;A variable of a struct type directly contains the data of the struct, whereas a variable of a class type contains a reference to the data, the latter known as an object.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lerping</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Website/post/lerping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 22:52:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Website/post/lerping/</guid>
      <description>What is Lerping? Lerp, or Linear Interpolation, is a mathematical function in Unity that returns a value between two others at a point on a linear scale.&#xA;Most commonly it’s used for moving or changing values over a period of time.&#xA;So when you are doing &amp;ldquo;Linear Interpolation&amp;rdquo; you are Linearly inserting a new point between 2 points. Linear Interpolation is inserting a new point between 2 points on a straight line.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Serialization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Website/post/serialization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 22:52:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Website/post/serialization/</guid>
      <description>What is Serialization? Serialization is the process of converting a data object which is a combination of code and data into a series of bytes which is saved as transmissible object. The data can then be transferred to another destination.&#xA;Why do we need to Serialize? Serialization enables us to save the state of an object and recreate the object in a new location.Serialization encompasses both the storage of the object and exchange of data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Serialization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Website/post/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 22:52:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Website/post/test/</guid>
      <description>Testing </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caching</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Website/post/caching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 22:03:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Website/post/caching/</guid>
      <description>Caching What is Caching? A cache is a high speed data storage which stores a subset of data, typically transient in nature, so that future requests for that data are served up faster than is possible by accessing the data’s primary storage location. Caching allows you to efficiently reuse previously retrieved or computed data.&#xA;How does Caching work? The data in a cache is generally stored in fast access hardware such as RAM (Random-access memory) and may also be used in correlation with a software component.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tower</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Website/projects/tower/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 22:37:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Website/projects/tower/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Implemented a simple prototype of a Tower Defense Game. Used Pathfinding Algorithms to create the enemy movement&#xA;https://github.com/kanand003/Tower</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My 1st post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Website/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Website/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is bold text, and this is emphasized text.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m going to start writing from today.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Website/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Website/about/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hi there I&amp;rsquo;m Anand Kumar, and I work as a Game Programmer.This website is a space where I can showcase my work, share my thoughts and ideas, and connect with others who share similar interests.&#xA;I specialize in creating gameplay mechanics, AI, user interfaces, and multiplayer networking. With a deep understanding of game engine development, I build custom tools to streamline development and optimize performance. I also collaborate effectively with artists for graphics development to bring game worlds to life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brick Breaker Game</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Website/projects/brick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Website/projects/brick/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is bold text, and this is emphasized text.&#xA;Developed A 2D Brick Breaker using OpenGL Framework. This was my first project with OpenGL api and was quite pleased with the final result&#xA;https://github.com/kanand003/BrickBreaker</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lily Game Engine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Website/projects/lily/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Website/projects/lily/</guid>
      <description>Introduction https://github.com/kanand003/Lily</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Website/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Website/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RayTracer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Website/projects/raytracer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Website/projects/raytracer/</guid>
      <description>A ray tracer summary</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wordle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Website/projects/wordle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Website/projects/wordle/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is bold text, and this is emphasized text.&#xA;Created a Desktop Version of wordle. Used SFML framework to help build the game. This took a period of 2 months to develop.&#xA;https://github.com/kanand003/WordleClone</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
