<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Anand Kumar</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/Website/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Anand Kumar</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 22:58:23 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/Website/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JSON Parser Implementation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Website/projects/json_parser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Website/projects/json_parser/</guid>
      <description>Project Overview This project implements a JSON parser in C# that transforms JSON text into usable data structures and vice versa. The implementation includes a lexer for tokenization, a parser for syntactic analysis, and a serializer for converting objects back to JSON text.&#xA;View on GitHub&#xA;Key Features Lexical analysis with comprehensive token handling Recursive descent parsing Support for all JSON data types Robust error handling Clean, maintainable code structure Implementation Details Basic Usage string json = &amp;#34;{ \&amp;#34;name\&amp;#34;: \&amp;#34;John\&amp;#34;, \&amp;#34;age\&amp;#34;: 30, \&amp;#34;isStudent\&amp;#34;: false }&amp;#34;; // Tokenize var lexer = new JsonLexer(json); var tokens = lexer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JSON Parsers: A Deep Dive</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Website/post/json_parser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 22:58:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Website/post/json_parser/</guid>
      <description>Introduction JSON (JavaScript Object Notation) has become the de facto standard for data exchange in modern web applications. A JSON parser is a crucial tool that transforms JSON text into usable data structures and vice versa. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how JSON parsers work, their importance, and the challenges in implementing one.&#xA;What is JSON? JSON is a lightweight, text-based data interchange format that&amp;rsquo;s easy for humans to read and write, and easy for machines to parse and generate.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
